Ashwin Thakur Curriculum Vitae

ashwin@thakur.co.nz // 021 188 0239 https://thakur.co.nz

Personal Details

Ashwin Thakur 28 Aspenleigh Drive Tamahere Hamilton 3283 (021) 188 0239

ashwin@thakur.co.nz

https://thakur.co.nz

New Zealand Citizen

Educational History

B.C.M.S (Bachelor of Computing and Mathematical Sciences) - Waikato University Major in Software Engineering - 4 Year Degree (Graduated 2002)

Career Summary

Year	Company	Position Held
Jan 2019 - Present	Livestock Improvement Automation	Software Developer
Jan 2013 - Dec 2019	Livestock Improvement	Rapid Prototyping Developer
Apr 2012 – Nov 2012	1-day/Torpedo 7	Web Developer
Jan 2004 - Nov 2012	Hill Laboratories	IT Programmer
Jan 2002 - Dec 2002	Hoare Research Software	Technical support person

Skills

- Latest frontend frameworks including React, Angular, VueJS for web & mobile development
- JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Knockout.js, Bootstrap
- IOS and Android Hybrid Mobile App Development including React Native & Ionic Framework
- Sound knowledge of .NET/Ruby/Node for Restful API and backend services
- Knowledge of AWS Services/Concourse for deployments, Docker/Vagrant for container management
- SQL experience with the following services Postgres, MongoDb, Redis
- Experience with Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Azure Devops
- Github (Gitlab), SVN (repositories)

Experience using programming languages, Javascript, Ruby, .NET, C++, Delphi, Java Also, have had experience in data migration of Excel/OpenOffice spreadsheets (via VBA macros with Excel, & OpenOffice macros)

Work Experience

Software Developer for Livestock Improvement Automation (Jan 2019 – Present)

.NET and Angular development with Azure DevOps, upgrading their core farm automation system (Protrack™). Agile processes such as team iteration planning and retrospective and a 3 monthly Pl Planning session were done consistently while implementing new features. Requirements were discussed closely with Product Owners/Product Design Analysts/Testers and other developers in delivering these core features.

Rapid Prototyping Developer for Livestock Improvement (LIC) (Jan 2013 – Dec 2019)

Responsible for building web applications with the use of UX best practice to deliver consumer-centric solutions. Worked with our core users (farmers) to paper-prototype, digital-prototype and then build solutions.

Core projects

- Pasture satellite integration with external parties (thru APIs) in delivering an auditing tool for our internal staff to help validate pasture reports for our external customers.
- Grazing planning mobile (Progressive web application) to help farmers manage their paddocks on their device with the help of LIC's core feed management system (MINDA Land & Feed).
- Web application for vets, being able view animal reproduction data across the vet's client farms, also having the ability to generate reports for their clients. This consisted of using the largest animal dataset in the country which provided animal health, reproduction information. Dataset was extracted daily and served onto the production server using enterprise service bus technology (Ruby).

<u>Web Developer for 1-day/Torpedo 7/Urbandaddy</u> (Apr – Nov 2012) (www.1-day.co.nz, www.torpedo7.co.nz, www.torpedo7.com.au)

.NET (MVC3) development which involved continuous improvement to website, other work included building a web application which used the Trademe & Quicksales (Australian auction site) API using .NET

Experience with Java/JSP Servlets, project work for 1-day mobile development, included constructing/developing a web application for the mobile platform.

Other support tasks given were email generation & website content update for Torpedo7 which was sent to over 100,000 users.

Worked in an agile environment using SCRUM, fortnightly sprints and daily morning catch-ups.

IT Programmer for Hills Laboratories (2004 - 2012)

Eight years' experience with the use of Delphi 5, 7 and 2006, 2010. This involved working on one of the most important and largest projects for the company, upgrading their laboratory system (LabSys2™ to LabSys3). The system was designed and built using object-oriented techniques with the use of several ActiveX controls and accesses an in-house database (Firebird).

The system itself (Labsys3) consisted of a wide range of features such as worksheet creation which then generated reports, invoices and quotes for our clients. The system also contained our client and staff contact information.

I was responsible for maintaining and upgrading the laboratory system after completion of the upgrade. All the code was written in-house and stored in a SVN repository (previously CVS) except for certain components (such as Report Builder/Fast Report/Express Spreadsheet).

<u>Technical support person for Hoare Research Software</u> (2002)

Primarily responsible for providing application support to HRS clients via phone/email.

The products were mathematics-based software for data analysis and modelling, such as Matlab, STATISTICA, Mathcad, Mathematica, ChemOffice, @RISK, Forecast Pro, SurveyPro. Other tasks included the maintenance of an existing 200-page website.

Achievements

- Chief Executive Award received for leading the implementation of the SPACE programme.
- Attended New Zealand Hi-Tech Awards in 2019 for the finalist in the category for Hi-Tech Solution for the Agritech Sector.

Hobbies

Other interests include rugby, league, cricket, poker and cryptic crosswords.

N.B. Further physical documentation is provided if needed, including university qualification, certificates, and achievements.

Referee(s) provided upon request.